[Music]
Super Vipin looking at
Bandra information
what are the complications
environment
region
action which is
applied to the
mentions the state give state
right and it takes an action date it's
applied to the environment and as an result
of applying this action environment change is
your state
history
then there is a designated stopping
state
you stop the trains okay means you can always do this it is right so when I say the
starting state it
jumps very well by a group of static
status and a group of static status I can always
define a dummy state which which
d status is right so I always have a single
starting state and a single stopping state
right so there are a lot of expressions so I say
bill cup saying date
mix items
multiple status where you bill stop you can
dummy state and say date automatically actually
rich one of d status you bill make a
translation
and apart from this it has also get a reward
signal  from the
and okay this is mention this is convenient
so modeling convenience date they put d
award and give environment okay date it is because they want to
put d award in an
place which is outside the agent direct
control
so it should get this award as a result
of d behavior in d world okay can't just
arbitrary set its one rewards
okay so date it is d region they put reward
in d environment okay sir it's outside in
reality right this bill could be a very match more complex
picture I have
bin repeat atley saying date which is
biological agent and reinforcement
learning agent right humans are
reinforcement learning agent so do you have a
separate reward conduit they have
rewards and singing
right so you only have what you sense from
d world right so you look around you see what
inputs are coming in
weather your engineering jump be interesting
food  You might be looking at the outside
world, right? Some remind me of touching you on a
screen, whatever. Right? So you're taking in these
complex sensory inputs and other kinds
of actual physical ingestible inputs, okay,
and you're converting them into reverse, right? So, if you're hungry and you think it's okay, rewarding, find out, right? So, if
you have a reward
scale of
10, not rewarding, just gives you something, so eat it, you just eat it, or you know, give
me company, and give
them some really bad food and things, like, right?
So, date is no immediate reward,
apart from company, part of it, but the
act of eating it is not giving
another immediate reward, but it probably has an
outcome in the long run, or it might eat some
fried food, just because your friend
asks you to, it probably has consequences in the
long run, right? So  Rewards and
IF IT and so they are going to make it very I am
going to say date it some
mechanism in d environment date gives ur
award it is rewards are ever asking this question where
rewards come
from
giving every where was comfort this
really think yes it's not very
clear so take it with d
pink of salt when I say date
environment is going to you give ur award
signal right what's jump comfort right in
fact and it's note and clear what is
d further and what is d and where
minute
so they have lot of robot
learning problem
really okay
train
object on d table
sir sister
think about it is note like okay it's a
robot you stage and everything outside d
robot
so it's note boundaries and note ask naturally
around d physical entities
right suppose suppose let consider about robot it
you are driving kar
okay so am i to do it
d further it what is  d ahead
and what is environment there
right no way always right answer is right but it
depends on right in this
how so ahead and jump b d tax
right give road right
so I d human being sitting and
driving ok what is d velocity which is
d tax moving ok and what is d
directions jumping in front of me right which
d things jump b
and environment right and d agent it
self is d tax controlling d tax on d
weather
right and agent cold b d human sitting
date and you can think about ok ho match ho
match pushing my
foot dr on d parallel which walking Should I be keeping me
fit on first how right
and give Should I be match what and what talk Should I
apply to you d steering wheel
right Should I be turning my head so look it right
today b looking
at friends right and Should I be looking at
me phone late so which of these things
decisions and you have  You make it right well you're
driving right so whether this is so interface no
d agent and what interface becomes a human when
d do right and it jump be and more
apps very I can give further back you can give further back
in d human right thinking about ok which ok I am
talking
fire no so dat
I turn d wheel disc match
right so which new launch should fire in my
motor I mean an autonomous nervous system so dat
I leg actually push dr with some kind
of pressure right so I jump like jump think
of defending on d kind of problem d
time solving dat I jump think of drawing
this agent and where but boundary anywhere and
not arbitrarily and but you can think of
multiple places where d se set of
interesting entities are der right but you have very different
kinds of modeling dat you do like it's not very
clear when I see tha an
agent in environment don't expect
people you come and give you ok this is d further
and  Here we go, no, come up with
reinforcement learning, solve this
problem, so typically
you have to think about this, figure out what is an
abstraction, date you would need right before
starting a solution, but this, so this is something which you have to know in
mind, you know one
of the ways of thinking about this, this
interaction proceeding, so model which, when they have been
living, you date is in agent, okay, it
senses, state of environment, it takes an
action, okay, and give date across,
change in the state of environment, so I
think of interaction proceeding like this, I have, yes
[music],
attack action, okay
new status
[music],
founding, you, the state and action, come time,
stable country,
arti, plus one, from,
typically, the next state, and the
next award, and determine, that, from
time, and date, but make most sense, you label
both of these, t +  1
ok
in d bonded how I was making an
distinction between n and di ok I am
going back to you sing every but d key jump b
discrim time sa well in fact per most of
d course
time time
pass
decision right
this is difficult ok some times I am
also interested in cases dat I don't take
other decisions with d state cup changing vote has
but per most parts when I say when
advanced steven wicked typically at d
point where I am required to take the
next decision ok so later they bill actually look at
style an discrim
how but where decisions did not happen at
every time take so they bill look at tha how sa well
later but not immediately ok but most
part of it
decision tick ok note a time tick tick was
necessity take d say time per example
consider game of k right so h move d you
make and so initially he bill b  making
moves very rapidly right because you're
playing from a standard opening
play something or letter on actually I have to study
both positions and then you have to
think about it and make moves like but I
style count everything
moves which count 1/4th of an move and anything because
you make decisions may also be non uniform
and not worry about it okay this is d
basic setting
no how long bill it take per d action you
complete
time so complete
[music]
religious following chapter 3 in d book right
and I did ask people you read ahead so
chapter three no
three
come so 4 people
so from no on start d chapter
religious assignment
bill let help program
stage in up
okay so what is it
d chapter say about robot
functions
learning
[music]
it put it mean
date agent cant arbitrary 70 what it has
you do it through the interaction with
The environment okay so the sessions dat you in
things dat they need so d more important
think her is d assumption dat d
award of scale number
week model per
rewards but if you remember they bill talk about a
wide variety of applications of
reinforcement writing in d first
lecture and which of d application
of dat variety of settings where you can use
scholar reward and gateway with right an but
fear and cases where you met how you make some kind
of calls about trade ops between ho
match importance you want you give you one
event versus inside come so per example let
again take d riching task they have right so when I want
you rich out you and ho it
set d award her what is
grasped I bill give an award after think when I suffer I need you
get d right so what I'm trying to do is
optimize function
very big d problem
you get
possible in d long  run right so if I don't give
another revert function
b happily moving weighing my hand round not doing anything about you
casting the
object let I need you give some kind of an
award here but grasping the object and whatever you would do this
negative reward at every time step eye cup
flaming around right it's like your
constant pain right and d pain bill stop once you have this right because
episode ends and stop getting
- 1 right so it's summary cups working with
n p jo d time cup ko ko and glue this is it ho way
train
or other other very other animal draws
a vehicle right cup pushing it in d side until
actually Richards d destination
sufficient
so you don't really want to strain your
hand right so I'm joint limits really don't want to lose like this right I have
go d phone right
no so you don't want to do date so you
want you give some kind of
additional fame  If I do things like this, but
I'm actually a bit careful, but so
you want to do this, communication is more important, and then you give it to me,
driving this thought, and then I say it gives you an award of
ten, right, and doing it gives
your award of ten, right, and then
one
optimal, right, so 99.1, I think you do it because I say getting it, take me, you get, and get
number,
Sudarshan, trade of alphabet, some point, right,
depends on the magnitude of the
reverse, I'm going to give you, well, so I'm
going to give you an eight thousand, right, doing something like this, right, give me, be more
careful,
and so this is what trade of right, when you
decide the problem, but you
set this award functions, I understand
problems like
grasping and reaching and robotics in
general, right, you can look at the problem, and then you're trying to
solve and try  You figure
out okay which are and disabled configuration okay so
very expensive robot so I don't want to
break it so let me make sure that this other
things have an extremely high negative
values ​​right and chip robot
mind throwing 300 boxers because it goes to cost only
₹1 give I can just not worry about
crashing and burning if you
along d way right so different
from d domain so the style significant
trade off you think about
instance where I would have you put
multiple outcomes right multiple outcomes on
d se scale
then it's a little tricky just like in this
how I mean dat is an outcome associated
with success which is grasping it and give
outcome associated with an well not really failures
but outcomes associated with
undesirable events along d way so I have you
put which of this on d se scale and I have
you do it might have  but more
convenient if you jump an thought of ok 100
on dat ok - 5 on this but just think dat in it avoid
non sir sensible where i can
communicate these things you d what
dat night butter mechanism it's
heart you come up proprietary optimization
setup but doing this so d scholar award
think a is pretty powerful and be
kid of gals and something ho they also do
decision making and d and of d they you are very good
act judging trade of right so when
d winner of s start thinking of doing something
you are putting this on d
on d to scale because there only d you can
think about trade out so in dat they also it s sims
you be natural and d third
think is having an single scholar value
max it edgier first you
optimize the solution right they can always get
APML solution but very serious so
scholar values ​​are fine late so I think dat is one of
d homework  Questions which you do
think about scholars is a little bit more I mean
think and reason about it and so what else do they need and what
you do
well
mathematics you be bound okay when you talk
about biological systems is not really
criteria because I mean it has to be
physical right so you can't have unbounded
new wells bike in your brain per
corresponding to award right so you mean just try
your brain it
but when talking about mathematics you
really want you want you be wanted
so basically let's say so one other think a letter
on
[music]
they would like rewards you be
frequent I explain this letter like wants
you start looking at learning
algorithms and but this essentially means date and it could be date I get
reward say once
in a million times steps very little very limited
literature in this right
so there is one alternative which people have
explained you look  Ate vector value
rewards very h component of d reward
correspondence you an different think dat you want
good and this are called typically multi
karate area
very fu paper which baby five and six
papers of d stock about multi karate a
reinforce in planning in fact
corresponding automatic also kale
multigraded and note me session let so where
people talk about different no of optimal
so what exactly is optical
right so optimal is where the objective
function riser minimum subjective function but
note fair when look and multiple dimensions
so you mean and preaching some kid of title
point also people talk about in
multi further and settings and looking at
more richer reward functions give and single
agent right
and
bill be interesting you come out with some kid
of quality
of looking at this kid an quantitative
feedback and if you like dat kid of k dewar
r dar is some kid of k in farsi
were  D feedback signal this signal note note
match again very little and things
which kids of k on like these all looking at
reward but look at d perception of
reward and Salman but who of dees r style her it
quantity but but once
in d million times steps something when
you bill never learn anything
rights and regardless what you do per
million times you get nothing
such you long and on the horizon you you learn anything over what so come so
your along d way okay so tha what
award
so policy so what is it and just talking about
different components of a
reinforcement learning system okay so they talk about
status and actions right basically
agent and they talking about d robot okay
next think I want to talk about c
policy so what is it d policy
sir so what is it d policy
so I am going to know d policy today an
conditional think from no on so what is this is
essential di so
probability date
probability
status
aa
material date they are right I bill b looking at
what are non stationary policies
what is stationary policy something which is
essential but
regardless of the value of ti I bill
b you think date from probability so d
probability date let see me state is one right
probability date when n give me d
symbol you use n state is l
ok
fine
d probability bill take so essentially what
time saying this probability was
you equal you
= 1 = probability date
nothing like this ok so this what I mean
by stationary thoughts what I have saying her so if I want
you to
explicitly talk about non stationary
policy ok I bill b the p t notation
policy
what is d goal and trying you come up with
d policy
[music]
brother good
and co you right time just defining
things right no stationary policy is just a
collection of functions collection of
probability distributions one per h
time step
Station
also set of probability distribution
14s
well s 14 was basically it ho you
drive ho you drive and on stationary
policy and ho you learn it from data and
other things they are independence question and just
talking about simple definition of d
quantity
policy welcome welcome
sir which you can learn right so I can have an
stationary policy run d full episode using
d stationary policy and give take d
rewards I get inside news d top
update in parameters and come up d new
stationary policy right so this time talking
about d t every is distinctly d index
over a single interaction
okay I am not talking about multiple
interaction over d single interaction
note I come and test plus over date
interaction in policy status
having an sequence of stationary policy
every
what date
suppose I am writing an cycle
date mean give you are temporary cake I am fool really good about
myself but give
inside vehicle and tree and building allover right and and
Getzer nahi so tha something dat gives
oo depends
but hopefully dat something dat bill dat you from doing crazy
things on d cycle d next
time around right so
d short term reward was just feeling good about
you per 1 minute and d long term
penalty was get
something and simple things like and k you know
d first think kids tree you capture
d queen and wholesale things and give sir
result
cancel don't look per short term rewards
you should look per something dat maximize is
your award hindi long term
[music]
[applause]